(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-29T09:03:51.774196",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
行くよ！
Here we go!
今日もこの胸は 張り詰めたまま
My heart is still beating anxiously today,
放課後に包まれて 君を見てる lady,ready?
enveloped after school, watching you. Lady, ready?
ずっと足並みは 揃わないまま
Our steps still out of sync,
続くからナイショだよ
it'll continue, so keep it a secret.
少しずつね lady,ready?
Little by little, lady, ready?
知りすぎて知らないから
Knowing too much makes me oblivious,
聞こえないふりが上手になって
and I've gotten good at pretending not to hear.
ねぇ深呼吸一息したら 目を開けて
Hey, take a deep breath, open your eyes,
呪文ジッと唱えて
and chant a spell.
なん気なくおはようって言っちゃってる
Casually blurting out a morning greeting.
飽きるくらい全部君が欲しいよ
I want all of you till I'm sick of it,
ハートは涙でいっぱい
my heart is full of tears.
恋のいろはとか まだわかってないんだ
I still don't understand the ABCs of love.
何度も繰り返すけど
I repeat it over and over,
寸前でまた次回へ
to be continued right before!
sweetな乙女心は
A sweet maiden's heart
あいにく取り扱っていないのです
is unfortunately not in stock.
ねぇ これが I love you?
Hey, is this "I love you"?
やっと手に入れたはずのパノラマ
Finally got a hold of this panorama,
二歩進み 二歩下がる
taking two steps forward, two steps back,
なんで?だけど lady, ready?
why? But lady, ready?
ゴールできなくちゃ止まれないから
I can't stop until I reach the goal!
わからないままでもね いいのだから lady, ready?
Even if I don't know, that's fine, so lady, ready?
昨日の答えなんてさ 壊しちゃった
Yesterday's answer... I've shattered it,
今日の答えの前では ほらね 壊しちゃった
before today's answer, look...
もう隠そうもないくらい好きだから
I like you so much I can't hide it anymore,
知らないことはいつか知れたらいいかななんて言っちゃおうかな
let's just say it's fine to learn what I don't know later!
とりとめないシーンでも大事だからねアンダーラインを引いて
Even uneventful scenes are important, so underline them.
恋の試験科目にも加えておいてよ
Add it to the test subjects of love!
時々君の心に何百マイルの distance?
Sometimes, how many miles is the distance to your heart?
なんてね気にしすぎかな だけどそれが本心なのです
Maybe I'm overthinking, but that's my true feeling.
こんな、あんな時はどうしたらいいの?
What should I do during times like this?
慣れたメロディを口ずさむように
Humming a familiar melody,
君の中の私はどこにいるの?
just where do I lie in your heart?
ぐるぐる回って四六時中、リサイタル!
Spinning round and round, all day and night, recital!
いつかその日が来たら大切な声を聞いて
When that day comes, listen to my precious voice,
恋に予約録画はありえないから逃がさないで
because you can't record love in advance, so don't miss it!
飽きるくらい全部君が好きだよ ハートは笑顔でいっぱい
I want you so much I could get tired of it, my heart is full of smiles!
恋の色はもう少し分かりたいんだ
I want to understand the colors of love a bit more.
何度も繰り返すけど寸前でまた次回へ
Repeating over and over, but right before it, back to next time!
sweetな乙女心は依然取り扱ってないのです ねえ、これがあいlove you?
A maiden's sweet heart still isn't handled... Hey, is this I love you?
Someday i really really send it, precious for you!
いっせーのせいで君とだけ!
On three, with just you!
もう少し眠りたいけど もったいないよ 今日はsunday
I want to sleep a bit more, but what a waste, today is Sunday!
楽しいこと やりたいこと wake up! 始めようよ
Fun things, things I want to do, wake up! Let's start!
めくるめく季節君と 次のステージへ
Through the revolving seasons, with you to the next stage!
声を合わせ 扉あけて 駆け出せ迷わずに
Matching our voices, opening the door, run forth without hesitation!
転んでもかっこ悪くてもイイじゃない
Even if we stumble or look uncool, isn't that fine?
stand up! イメージもっと重ねて行くその先で
Stand up! Layering our images even more, beyond that point!
いっせーのせいで君とだけ!
On three, with just you!
ハイタッチ 手たたいて 奏でるメロディを合図に走り出せ go!
High-touch, clapping hands, run out to the melody we play as our signal, go!
君とならこわくない
With you, I'm not afraid!
ハイタッチ 手と手 たたいて 重ねるそのメモリーは明日へのエネルギー yeah! さあ行こうよ
High-touch, hand in hand, clapping, those memories we stack are our energy for tomorrow, yeah! Let's go!
もっと先へ 君となら happy lucky life!
Further ahead, with you, happy lucky life!
あの日見た夢の続き 追いかけるその日まで
Until the day we chase the continuation of the dream we saw that day,
涙なんて振り切るくらい もっとスピードアップ!!
Shake off tears and speed up even more!!
どんな未来になっても後悔しないよ
No matter what future awaits, I won't regret it!
どんな未来になっても
No matter what future awaits us,
後悔しないよ
I have no regrets.
自分自身選んだ道
Take a step on the path you chose,
踏み出せ迷わずに
without hesitation.
落ち込んで進めなくなった時は
When you're feeling down and can't move forward,
Wake up! 思い出す夢見た頃の記憶を
Wake up! Recall the memories of when you dreamed.
手と手で奏でる叶えきらめく夢は君とだけ
Hand in hand, playing and fulfilling that glittering dream with just you!
ハイタッチその度に繋がって行く心
High touch! Each time, our hearts connect more,
一人じゃないことをそう気づかせてくれたよね
Reminding me that I'm not alone, you know?
ハイタッチ手と手たたいて奏でるそのメロディーが
High touch! Hand in hand clapping, playing that melody
世界に届くまではいこの夢は続いてく
Until it reaches the world, yes, this dream will go on.
君とならハッピーラッキーライフ！
With you, it's a happy lucky life!
くじいて歩けない日はおんぶしてあげる君を
On days when you're crushed and can't walk, I'll carry you on my back.
ほら見てそっちの方が強く地面踏み込める
Look, from that side you can stomp the ground even stronger!
巡り巡る日々を辿り夢見たステージへ
Tracing through revolving days to the stage we dreamed of,
届くその日を見つめて起こそう君とだけ！
Gazing at the day it reaches, let's make it happen with just you!
手と手を鳴らすたび小さなビッグバン
Every time our hands clap, a tiny big bang occurs,
無限のその力を受けて進め！！
Receive that infinite power and move forward!!
ハイタッチ手と手たたいて奏でるメロディーを
High touch! Hand in hand clapping, playing the melody,
合図に走り出せこう君となら怖くない
Run out at the signal, with you like this I'm not afraid.
ハイタッチ手と手たたいて重ねるそのメモリーは
High touch! Hand in hand clapping, piling up those memories,
明日へのエネルギーさあ行こうよもっと先へ
Energy for tomorrow, come on, let's go even further ahead.
君とならハッピーラッキーライフ！
With you, it's a happy lucky life!
どーも皆さん見てますかー？
Hello everyone, are you watching?
だよー、ということで
Yeah, so...
ホロライブ2期生の
Hololive 2nd Generation's
百鬼あやめです！
Nakiri Ayame here!
イェーイ、見てる？
Yay, are you watching?
ということでですね、あ、ちょっと歌って
So, um, after singing and dancing,
あのヘトヘトなんですけど、一曲目は...
I'm pretty exhausted, but the first song...
Q&Aリサイタルで、二曲目は
was Q&A Recital, and the second song
ハイタッチメモリーを踊らせていただきました！
was High Touch Memory!
今日はね、本当は9月13日なんだけど
Today, actually, it's supposed to be September 13th,
10月2日に3Dで3周年記念ライブを...
but we're doing the 3rd anniversary 3D live on October 2nd...
記念ライブしていきたいと思います！
holding this commemorative live! Yay!
ということで今日は、ゲストをたくさん呼んでいるので
So today, since we're inviting lots of guests,
ま、今日のね、放送の最後には嬉しいお知らせも、
at the end of today's broadcast, there might be happy news,
あったりなかったりするので、最後まで見ててね！
or maybe not, so make sure to watch until the end!
じゃあもうジャンジャンね、ちょっとゲストと一緒に歌って踊っていっちゃおうかなと！
So let's keep going and sing and dance with our guests!
ま、誰が来るのか、みんな予想しておいてね！
Guess who's coming, everyone!
じゃあ早速1人目を呼んでいっちゃおうかなと思いまーすよ！
Now, let's call our first guest right away!
ということで、1人目は――！
So, the first one is...!
おかゆー！
Okayu!
イェーイ！
Yay!
来てくれてありがとう！
Thank you for coming!
来たいって言ってくれたから！
You said you wanted to come!
ということで、今日はおかゆが来てくれましたー！
So today, Okayu has come to join us!
イェーイ！おかゆちゃん3周年おめでとう！
Yay! Okayu-chan, congratulations on your 3rd anniversary!
ありがとう！イェーイ！
Thank you! Yay!
なんかさ、おかゆってさ、ご飯行ったりとかさ、遊んだりしてるじゃん、ゲームしたりね。
You know, Okayu and I go out to eat and hang out, playing games together.
ゲームしてるんだけど、あんまり意外に3Dで歌って踊ることなくて。確かに。
We play games, but surprisingly we've never really sung and danced in 3D together. True.
今日が初めてらしいです。
Apparently today is the first time.
の割にノリもいいもんね。ちょっとあの、スクショとか撮っていってくださいね。
Even so, you've got great rhythm. Please take lots of screenshots!
今日はね、歌って踊るわけなんだけど
Today we're singing and dancing,
おかゆと何歌って踊ろうかなって考えたときに
and when I thought about what song to sing and dance with Okayu,
おかゆがね、この曲をね、「ちゃんと一緒に歌って踊りたいんだよね」って。
Okayu said, 'I really want to sing and dance to this song together with you!'
それを今日一緒に歌いたいと思います！やったー！
So we're going to sing it together today! Yay!
というわけで、早速歌っちゃいますか！
So, shall we get right into singing it?
いっちゃいますか！
Shall we?
じゃあ行きますよー！
Here we go!
レッツゴー！
Let's go!
言って
Say it
あのね、私、実は気付いてるの
Hey, you know, I've actually realized it...
ほら、君が言ったこと
Look, what you said...
あまり考えたいと思えなくて
That I couldn't bear to think about it much,
忘れてたんだ けど
And had forgotten about it, but...
盲目的に 盲動的に 妄想的に生きて
Living blindly, recklessly, full of delusions,
衝動的な 焦燥的な 消極的なままじゃダメだったんだ
Impulse, impatience, and negativity—it was no good.
きっと、人生最後の日を前に思うのだろう
Surely, before the final day of my life, I'll think...
全部、全部言い足りなくて惜しいけど
That I didn't get to say everything, everything, and it's a pity, but—
ああ、いつか人生最後の日 君がいないことを
Ah, someday on the last day of my life, that you won't be here...
もっと、もっと、もっと、もっと、ちゃんと言って
Tell me more, more, more, more, properly.
あのね、
Hey, you know...
空が青いのってどうやって伝えればいいんだろうね
How should I convey to you how blue the sky is?
夜の雲が高いのってどうすれば君もわかるんだろう
What should I do so you can understand how high the night clouds are?
言って
Say it.
あのね、
Hey, you know...
私、実は分かってるの もう君が逝ったこと
I actually already know that you've already passed on.
あのね、わからず屋って言うんだろうね
You'd probably call me a stubborn blockhead, right?
忘れたいんだけど
I want to forget, but—
もっとちゃんと言ってよ 忘れないようメモにしてよ
Tell me properly, make a memo so I won't forget.
明日十時にホームで待ち合わせとかしよう
Let's promise to meet at the station platform at 10 tomorrow.
牡丹は散っても花だ 夏が去っても追慕は切だ
Even if peonies scatter, they're still flowers; even when summer passes, longing is sharp.
口に出して 声に出して 君が言って
Put it into words, say it out loud, you say it.
そして人生最後の日 君が見えるのなら
And on the final day of my life, if I can see you,
きっと、人生最後の日も愛を歌うのだろう
Surely, on the final day of my life as well, I'll be singing of love.
全部、全部無駄じゃなかったって言うから
Because I'll say that none of it, none of it was in vain—
ああ、いつか人生最後の日 君がいないことが まだ信じられないけど
Ah, someday on the last day of my life, I still won't be able to believe you're gone, but—
もっと、もっと、もっと、もっと、ちゃんと言って
More, more, more, more, properly tell me...
次
Next...
のゲストも
is there a guest too?
いるのかな？
I wonder...
あ、あ、あ、
Oh, oh, oh!
あ、なんかちょっと準備が
Ah, it seems preparations
できたそうなので、
are ready,
2曲目も呼んでいっちゃおうかなと、
let's call on the second song too!
思いますよ！
I will!
ころねー！
Korone!
わあ！
Yay!
こんな、こんなめでたい時に呼んでくれて、
Thank you for calling me when I'm so happy!
ありがとうございます。
Thank you so much!
いいや、ありがとうございます。来てくれて、ありがとう、本当に。
Thank you! Thank you so much for coming!
ありがとうございます。ありがとうございます。
Thank you so much, yes.
今日はね、
Today...
あの、一緒にね、歌って踊りたい曲があったんだってね。
we have a song we want to sing and dance to together, you know?
あるんですよ。
There is!
あるんだよ。ちょっとね、
There is, so...
言ってやってくださいよ。
Please tell us!
え、もう曲、踊る曲言っちゃっていいんですか？
Eh, the song to dance to, is it okay?
あの、なんか頑張ったこと言ってあげてくださいよ。
Uh, please say what you worked hard on!
そうだね。なんかすっそり一緒に転んでと、
That's right, we secretly rolled together...
ダンスレッスンをね、ちょっとこっそりしたんですよ。
We secretly practiced the dance lessons together!
一緒に、ねえ、踊りたいなと。
We want to dance together,
ダンスちょっとね、苦手なんですけど、
dance is a bit of a weak point for me, but...
ちょっと、ころねとやりたいなと思って、一生懸命練習してきました！
I wanted to do Luka Luka Night Fever, so I practiced really hard!
なので、それをね、お披露目、お披露目したいと、頑張っているところを、
So I want to unveil that, show everyone where I'm working hard,
みんな、ちゃんと見ててくださいね。
and everyone, please watch properly!
いけいけよ。いけいけよ。
Yes, yes, yes.
というわけで、じゃあ行っちゃいますか！
With that said, shall we get going?
はい！
Yes!
ミュージック、スタート！
Music, start!
ダメダメよ☆
No, no, no, no, no! ☆
右から左へと言葉が流れる
Words flow from right to left
退屈そうな顔 画面見つめる君に
That bored look on your face as you watch the screen
次元の壁越えて いつでも逢いに行く
Crossing the dimensional wall, I'll go meet you anytime
心の準備をちゃんとしておいてね
Prepare yourself properly in your heart!
君のこと誰よりも分かってる だから私に任せて
I know you better than anyone, so leave it to me!
怖がらないで二人で踊りましょう！
Don't be scared, let's dance together!
ルカルカ★ナイトフィーバー
Luka Luka Night Fever
はじけるリズムに合わせて 嫌なこと何もかも全部忘れて
In time to the popping rhythm, forget all your troubles now!
ルカルカ★ナイトフィーバー
Luka Luka Night Fever
私はここに居るから 少しでも視線を逸らしちゃダメダメよ☆
I'll be right here, don't you look away, no, no, no, no, no! ☆
重くて見れない日 兄貴に釣られた日
When it's heavy and you can't see, when you're teased by your older brother
心で呼んでみて すぐに飛んで行くわ
Call me from your heart and I'll fly right to you!
授業では教わらないことを君に教えてあげるわ
I'll teach you things you won't learn at school!
夜の扉を二人で開きましょう
Let's open the night's door together!
あふれる想いはFor You
Overflowing feelings are for you
限りあるこの時を胸に刻んで
Engraving this limited time in our hearts
ルカルカ★ナイトフィーバー 朝日が昇ればサヨナラ
Luka Luka Night Fever, when the morning sun rises, it's goodbye
寂しそうなそんな目 されてもダメだから
Even if you give me that lonely look...
君のこと誰よりも分かってる だからすべてをお皿して
I know you better than anyone, so let's clear everything away
生まれた意味を二人で見つけましょう！
and find the meaning of birth together!
ルカルカ★ナイトフィーバー
Luka Luka Night Fever
高まる鼓動を感じて さあ覚悟できたらこの手をとって...
Feeling the pounding heartbeat, if you're ready, take my hand...
ルカルカ★ナイトフィーバー
Luka Luka Night Fever
輝く君が大好きなの 全力で飛び出そう
I love you when you shine, let's jump out with all our might!
用意はいいかしら？
Are you ready?
ルカルカ★ナイトフィーバー
Luka Luka Night Fever
はじけるリズムに合わせて 嫌なこと何もかも全部忘れて
In time to the popping rhythm, forget all your troubles now!
ルカルカ★ナイトフィーバー 私はここに居るから 少しでも視線を逸らしちゃダメダメよ☆
Luka Luka Night Fever, I'm right here so don't look away, no, no, no, no, no! ☆
ダメダメよ☆
Don't take your eyes off me☆
ebb and flow
作詞:川田まみ 作曲:中沢伴行
[Title: ebb and flow / Lyrics: Mamami Kawada / Music: Takayuki Nakazawa]
降り積もる粉雪が舞う
The powdery snow piles up and dances,
諦めかけた夢がまた波打つ
dreams that were almost given up on stir once more.
あの日のままで変わらない笑顔見つめた
Just like that day, I gazed at your unchanging smile.
染まる頬に触れた風が空高く抜け立った
The wind that touched my cheeks soared high into the sky.
いつも見ていた...
Always watching...
近いようで遠くて
Seemingly close yet far away,
いつだって、届かない...
always out of reach...
どうして?と問いかけた声も揺れる
Why? Even the questioning voice wavers.
ゆらゆら水面に浮かんだ月は
The moon that floats on the swaying water surface
何も語らないただの傍観者
doesn't say anything, a mere observer.
「同じね」
"Same here."
握る手が痛い
The hand I hold hurts.
いたずらに風が吹く朝
Mischievously, the wind blows in the morning,
樹々の葉がじゃれあう声に合わせて
as the leaves of the trees rustle together.
駆け出す君をただ夢中で追いかけていた
I chased after you in a daze as you ran off.
その横顔が見てるのは遥か遠くここじゃなくて
The profile I see is far away, not here.
海が満ち、また引いていく夕凪
The sea fills up, then recedes in the evening calm.
心の岸に打ち寄せられた決意は明日の光
The determination in my heart is the light towards tomorrow—
信じて
believe in it.
ねぇ
Hey,
問いかけた声が響く
the questioning voice echoes.
はらほらと一緒に夜空駆けでいけば
If we run together into the night sky, fluttering,
あの丘に日差しの差す頃に
by the time the sunlight shines on that hill...
「見つけた」
"I found it."
願いは宝石輝き出す ah
Wishes sparkle like jewels, ah...
the ebb and flow of my mind...
降り積もる粉雪が舞う
Falling powdery snow dances around,
諦めかけた夢がまた波打つ
The dream I almost gave up on heaves once more.
あの日のままで 変わらない笑顔見つめた
I looked at your unchanging smile, just like that day.
染まる頬に触れた風が 空高く抜けた
The wind touching my flushed cheeks swept high into the sky.
いつも見ていた 近いようで遠くて
I was always watching you. You felt close yet so far.
いつだって 届かない...
No matter when, I can never reach you...
どうして? と
"Why?"
問いかけた声も揺れる
My questioning voice trembles as well.
ゆらゆら水面に浮かんだ月は何も
The moon floating unsteadily on the water's surface
語らない ただの傍観者
says nothing, acting as a mere bystander.
「同じね」 握る手が痛い
"We're the same, aren't we?" My gripping hand aches.
いたずらに風が吹く朝
On a morning when the wind blows playfully,
樹々の葉がじゃれあう声に合わせて 駆け出す君を
matching the rustling chatter of the tree leaves, I start running after you.
ただ夢中で追いかけていた
I was simply chasing after you in a daze.
その横顔が見てるのは 遥か遠く ここじゃなくて
Your profile is gazing far away, not here.
海が満ち、また引いていく夕凪
An evening calm where the sea tide rises and recedes again.
心の岸に打ち寄せられた決意は明日の光 信じて
My resolve, washed ashore on the coast of my heart, believes in tomorrow's light.
ねぇ 問いかけた声が響く
Hey, your questioning voice echoes out.
誰かの描いたシナリオじゃなくて
Instead of a scenario drawn by someone else,
私たちの道見つけたい
I want to find our own path.
誰だって探してる 自分だけのストーリー
Everyone is searching for their very own story,
ウワサだけを頼りに飛び回る蝶みたい
like butterflies fluttering about, relying only on rumors.
夜の路地裏 静かな公園
Night alleyways, a quiet park,
駅の雑踏 心の隙間
the station crowds, the gaps in the heart.
何もかもを横目に置いていく
Leaving everything else aside and passing them by,
ただ一つの「ホント」を手に入れるために
just to get my hands on that one single truth.
流れて行く前に 消えて行く前に
Before it flows away, before it fades away,
知らない未来があるのなら
if there is an unknown future waiting for us.
誰かの描いたシナリオじゃなくて
Instead of a scenario drawn by someone else,
手を繋いだままで進める 私たちの道見つけたい
I want to find our path where we can keep moving forward hand in hand.
誰だって迷ってる
Everyone is lost
自分だけのラビリンス 地図もない狭い暗い世界 扉はどこに?
in their own labyrinth—a narrow, dark world with no map. Where is the door?
読みかけのブック 破れた日記
A half-read book, a tattered diary,
書きかけの詩 心の所在
a half-written poem, the whereabouts of the heart.
どれも全部残して行くけど
Though we leave all of those behind,
ただ一つの「キボウ」は抱えて行くから
we will hold onto that one single hope as we go.
遥か遠い先に
Far off in the distance,
辿り着く先に 知らない未来があるのなら
at the destination we finally reach, if an unknown future awaits us,
誰かの望んだシナリオじゃなくて
instead of a scenario wished for by someone else,
目を凝らしてはじめて見える 私たちの道見つけたい
I want to find our path, visible only when we strain our eyes.
おいてく風景も 残した想いも
The scenery left behind, the feelings left behind,
心の隙間も ありかも
and the gaps in my heart might be alright too.
全部が全部 いつかきらめいて 自分の後ろにできる足跡
All of it will someday shine as the footprints left behind me.
流れてくとしても 消えてゆくとしても
Even if it flows away, even if it fades away,
知りたい未来があるのなら
if there is a future I want to know,
誰かの描いたシナリオじゃなくて 手を繋いだままで進める
rather than someone else's scenario, we can move forward holding hands.
私たちの道見つけて
Finding our own path...
ちょっと教会のほうで一人でエモい曲をちょっと歌わせていただいたんですけども！
I just got to sing an emotional song all by myself over at the church!
まだまだ続きますよここからも！ちょっとねまだゲストもまだまだちょっとひかえて
It's going to keep going from here too! We still have guests waiting backstage,
いるのでね、ちょっと早速、早速なんですけど、お、あれ？ゲスト3人目ですね！3人目のゲスト、ちょっと呼んで、早速歌っていきたいと思いますよ！
so let's get right into it. Oh? It's the 3rd guest! Let's call out the 3rd guest and get right to singing!
じゃあちょっと3人目は一体誰が来るんでしょうか！
Now then, who on earth could this 3rd guest be?!
うわーー！どきどきーー！のいちゃんだーー！
Waaah! So exciting! It's Noel-chan!
今か今かとずっと待ってました！だんちょうでーす！
I've been waiting and waiting for this! It's the commander!
イェーイ！ありがと来てくれて！
Yay! Thanks for coming!
駆けつけますよー！
I rushed right over!
いやもうそんなんね、あやめ先輩の3周年だったらもう喜んで駆け付けますどこにいても！
For Ayame-senpai's 3rd anniversary, I'd gladly rush over no matter where I am!
え、いいんですかそんな！当たり前じゃないですか！
Eh, really?! Of course! Isn't that obvious?!
でもなんかちょっと最近よく一緒に、確かに！3Dをしているじゃないですか！うれしいな！今日もご一緒していただきありがとうございます！
Lately we've been doing 3D together quite a bit, right? I'm so happy! Thank you for joining me today!
今日もねちょっと可愛い曲をのいちゃんと一緒に歌って踊っちゃお、チョコレート！おもいまっすよー！
Today too, Noel-chan and I will sing and dance to a cute song... Chocolate! Let's do it!
じゃあ早速いきますか！お、行きますか？
Shall we get right to it then? Oh, shall we go?
よし、ミュージッ、く、スタート！
Alright, music... start!
ねぇ歌うわ
Hey, I'll sing,
そうよあなたに甘えたいけれど恥ずかしいかもね
that's right, I want to lean on you, but I might be too shy.
かもね！ハイ！
Maybe! Hai!
願いごとの注文はニャムニャムニャムニャム
My wished-for spell is nyamu nyamu nyamu nyamu!
ずっとこのまま時が止まらぬかもね
I hope this time won't ever stop, maybe!
こういうのが恋なのドキドキキーン
Is this what love feels like? Doki doki keen!
しかもね！
And what's more, maybe!
スキスキスキ
Suki suki suki!
昨日よりも... かもね！
More than yesterday... maybe!
ねぇ歌ってそうよあなたも
Hey, sing too, you as well,
乙女の気持ちが伝わるといいな
I hope a maiden's feelings reach you!
喉から出そうなぐらいもうラブラブラブ
It feels like it's right in my throat, love love love!
ずっとこのままあなた素敵がいいな
I hope you stay wonderful forever like this!
こういうのは初めてドキドキキーン
This is my first time feeling like this, doki doki keen!
あいな！
So nice!
スキスキスキ
Suki suki suki!
さっきよりも... いいな！
Even more than before... great!
そんな曲が歌えちゃうなんて、嬉しいです。いや、ありがとうございます。
I'm so happy I can sing a song like that. No, thank you.
こちらこそいつもいつも、なんていうか。ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much, as always... Thank you!
いや、先週はね、団長の2周年ライブに来て下さり
Well, last week, you came to my 2nd anniversary live...
なんとね、本当ありがとうございます。
and seriously, thank you so much.
今回は3周年ライブに団長をお呼び出しして、すごく嬉しいです！
I'm so happy you invited me to your 3rd anniversary live this time!
いや、ありがとうございます！呼んできてくれて嬉しい、ありがとう！
No, thank you! I'm so happy you invited me, thank you!
あやめ先輩、気づいてましたか？
Ayame-senpai, did you notice?
なんですか？
Notice what?
団長たち2人でこうライブをすると、いつもこういう会話しかしてないです。
Whenever the two of us do a live together like this, we always end up having this exact conversation.
そうだね、いつもあたりさわりない会話になっちゃってるね。
That's true, it always turns into such superficial small talk.
そう。団長、あやめ先輩が好きすぎて、あの目の前に来ると、こういう会話しかできなくなる。トークスキルがゼロになっちゃうんです。
Yeah. I love Ayame-senpai so much that whenever she gets right in front of me, I can only have conversations like this. My talk skills drop to zero.
まあ、よもや、元々ないみたいなとこあるからさ、はい、けれど。
Well, it's not like you had any to begin with, right? Haha, but yeah.
え、ほろめんでトークスキルがあるって言ったら誰を思い浮かべます？
Eh, if you talk about Holomem with good talk skills, who comes to mind?
そうだね、やっぱマリンちゃんかな。
Let's see, probably Marine-chan.
やっぱマリンですよね。
Yeah, definitely Marine.
いや、ちょっと悔しいけど、ちょっとマリンのいないところだから言うけど、マリンのトークは上手だもんね。すごいよなぁ、本当に尊敬するな。
Man, it's frustrating, but since Marine isn't here, I'll say it—Marine's talk is really good. It's amazing, I really respect her.
うらやましいとこやっぱあるよね。羨ましい。今もほしいなマリンのトークスキル。
There are definitely parts of her I envy. So envious. I want Marine's talk skills right now too.
あれ？いつの間にか。
Huh? Without even noticing...
あやめ先輩がこんなに求めてくれてるから来ちゃいました！
Since Ayame-senpai wanted me here so much, I came running!
え？みんな、え、何しょ？
Eh? Everyone, eh, what are you...
団長、まだあやめ先輩と…ちょっとちょっと、前の方へ！前の方へよ！
Dancho, you're still with Ayame-senpai... Wait, wait, come forward! Come forward!
いや、前の方へよ！
Come forward!
なんかこれ、なんだこれ？あれ、もしや２人で歌う感じですか、この後。
What is this? What is this? Wait, are the two of you going to sing a song after this?
え？え？いや、いま私が呼んだの！
Eh? Eh? No, I'm the one who called her!
いや、いま私が呼んだんだよ！本当は言ってくれればよかったのに。え、じゃあ三人で歌うって感じかな？いや、あ、そうそうそうって感じ。
No, I called her! You could have just told me. Eh, so we're singing as a trio? Ah, yeah yeah yeah, exactly.
じゃあ、ちょっと団長名残惜しいけど、あやめ先輩のライブ最高にしたいから二人で、はい、見てます。センターで。邪魔邪魔邪魔、ローマンここで見ろ。３周年おめでとうございます！ありがとうございます！
Well, Dancho, it's a bit bittersweet, but we want to make Ayame-senpai's live the best, so the two of us will watch. From the center. Outta the way, watch from over here, Roman. Happy 3rd anniversary! Thank you!
気をつけてね！ありがとう！
Take care! Thank you!
消えちゃった。二人きりですね。うん。二人きりですね。うん。ヌードが。
They disappeared. It's just the two of us. Yep. Just the two of us. Yep. Nude...
あやめ先輩、なんか、あれ？これ並んでると何か、あ、なんかお気づきになりませんか？え、何ですか？なんだか、なんだか私たちって、
Ayame-senpai, like, huh? When we line up like this, do you notice anything? Eh, what is it? Somehow, we...
姉妹みたいじゃない？
Look like sisters, don't we?
嫌な顔するな。賢者するな。
Don't make that disgusted face. Don't act all wise.
キミがいないと 何もできないよ
Without you, I can't do anything
キミのごはんが 食べたいよ
I want to eat your home-cooked meal
もしキミが 帰ってきたら とびっきりの笑顔で 抱きつくよ！
If you come back, I'll hug you with a huge smile!
キミがいないと 謝れないよ
Without you, I can't apologize
キミの声が 聞きたいよ
I want to hear your voice
キミの笑顔が 見れれば それだけでいいんだよ
If I can see your smile, that's all I need
キミがそばにいるだけで
Just having you by my side
いつも勇気をもらってた
Always gave me courage
いつまででも 一緒にいたい
I want to be together forever
この気持ちを 伝えたいよ
I want to convey this feeling
晴れの日にも 雨の日にも キミはそばにいてくれた
On sunny days and rainy days, you were by my side
目を閉じれば キミの笑顔 輝いてるよ
When I close my eyes, your smile shines brightly
キミがいないと 何もわからないよ
Without you, I don't understand anything
砂糖としょうゆは どこだっけ？
Where are the sugar and soy sauce?
もしキミが 帰ってきたら びっくりさせようと 思ったのに…
If you come back, I thought I'd surprise you...
キミについについ 甘えちゃうよ
I always end up relying on you
キミが優しすぎるから
Because you're far too kind
キミにもらってばかりで なにもあげられてないよ
I only receive from you, and I haven't given anything back
当たり前に思ってた こんな日々がずっとずっと
I took for granted that these days would go on forever...
続くんだと思ってたよ
Thinking they would last and last.
ごめん 今は気づいたよ
I'm sorry, but now I realize
当たり前じゃないことに
that this isn't just a given.
まずは君に伝えなくちゃ
First, I have to tell you—
「ありがとう…」
"Thank you..."
君の胸に届くかな 今は自信ないけれど
I wonder if it reaches your heart. Though I'm not confident right now,
笑わないでどうか聞いて 想いを歌に込めたから
please don't laugh and just listen, as I've put my feelings into this song.
ありったけのありがとうを 歌にのせて届けたい
I want to deliver all my thanks through this song,
この気持ちは ずっとずっと 忘れないよ
and I will never, ever forget these feelings.
届けー！！
Reach them!!
なんかちょっとバラバラだったね、ちょっとね。
That was kind of all over the place, wasn't it?
ちょっと心がまだ通じ合ってなかったね。
Our hearts weren't quite in sync yet.
心配はせん、ちょっと。これからどんどん心の距離を...ちょっと待って。
Don't worry. From now on, our hearts' distance will... Wait a second.
大丈夫か？歌って踊ってない。
Are you okay? You're not even singing and dancing!
ちょっと心拍数の距離を縮めるために...
To narrow the distance of our heart rates...
これやっぱり姉妹でしょ？
Aren't we sisters, after all?
ちょっと似てるかもね。
We might look a little alike.
本当に今日は来てくれてありがとう！
Thank you so much for coming today!
お前が呼んだんだろ！逃げるな！逃げたね！
You're the one who called us! Don't run away! You ran!
逃げないで！すいません！許して！
Don't run away! I'm sorry! Forgive me!
ありがとうございました！どこまでも追いかけるぞ！
Thank you very much! We'll chase you to the ends of the earth!
見当たらない！いない！
I can't find it! It's not here!
え、本当にいるのそんなの？ここに小さいナキリがいるっていう...じょうが...
Wait, is there really something like that? Saying there's a tiny Nakiri here...
それどれくらいの確率ででるのそんなの？60%だって！60%ネットで...
What's the probability of that spawning? 60% online, it says 60%!
そんなでるの！？いないじゃん！
It spawns that much?! It's not here!
なんか通しすぎた...通しすぎた...
We went past it... We went right past it!
もしかして...でもこれは大きいな。
Could it be... But this one is huge.
どれがナキリだ？あれ？小さいナキリじゃない。
Which one is Nakiri? Huh? That's not the small Nakiri.
レアだ！レアナキリだ！
It's rare! It's a rare Nakiri!
レアナキリだ！握手おねがいします！どうもどうもどうもどうも！ゲット！
A rare Nakiri! Please shake my hand! Thank you, thank you! Got it!
すごいなレア！やったな！
That's amazing, rare! We did it!
なんか小さいナキリが出るって...そう、小さいナキリが出るんだよ。
They said a small Nakiri appears... Yes, a small Nakiri appears.
でもおっきいナキリって...おっきいナキリなんてあるのかなと思ってさ、なんで欲しってきたんですか今？
But a big Nakiri... I wondered if there even was a big Nakiri, why did you come looking for it just now?
そうだよ。あのね、さっきね、ちょっとマリンちゃんに追いかけ回されててね。
That's right. You see, earlier, Marine-chan was chasing me around.
え、怖い！歌って踊ってたんですよ、よ。
Eh, scary! We were singing and dancing, you know.
え、歌って踊ってたの？え、なんで歌って踊ってたの？
Huh, you were singing and dancing? Why were you singing and dancing?
実はね、デビュー日からちょっと3周年なんですよ！
Actually, it's been about 3 years since our debut!
おめでとう！おめでとう！すごい！おめでとう！
Congratulations! Congratulations! Amazing, congratulations!
じゃあ私たちもね、なんかしょっぱなにね、
Well, then, right from the start, we also...
踊ったりとかして...いいんですか？やってみましょうかじゃあ。
Danced and stuff... Is that okay? Shall we try it then?
どのよりもちょうど、でもそれ...やめてませーん！
More than anything... wait, stop it!
センター、センター、センター！
Center, center, center!
で、キュッってね。そう、うちはキュッ、ふいっとね。ふいっとね。
And then "squeeze". Right, we do "squeeze", "swoosh". "Swoosh".
お、ふいっとね。
Oh, "swoosh".
じゃあ行きますよ！せーの！百花繚乱花吹雪！
Here we go! Ready, set! Hyakka Roran Hanafubuki!
色づく想いは切ない 百花繚乱花吹雪
Feelings tinged with color are bittersweet, a riot of hundred flowers, a blizzard of petals.
パッと咲いて散った 花は終わり実をつけてく
Blossoms that burst and scatter come to an end, bearing fruit.
その時を待てど暮らせど 事は進まず
Waiting for that time, yet nothing moves forward.
そっと触れて知った 胸の中の温かさは
Gently touching, I learned the warmth inside my breast—
初めてのこの気持ちだけ 抱きしめていたい
wanting only to hold close this brand-new feeling.
暁交わした約束は “本物”だってきっと信じてる
I surely believe the promise exchanged at dawn is "real."
色はにほへと の花に魅せられた少女たち
Maidens charmed by the fragrant, colorful blossoms—
ああ はらり はらり はらり 落ちる花と舞い踊れ
ah, flutter, flutter, falling petals, dance away!
惑わされずとも想い 言の葉に込めてみた
Though unstaggered, I put my feelings into words.
誰も皆焦がれ出る 現世の理よ
All yearning is the principle of this mortal world.
色づく想いは切ない 百花繚乱 花吹雪
Colored thoughts are painful; a hundred flowers bloom in a storm of cherry blossoms.
フッと引き消した 夜を戸惑う 月明かりに
In the moonlight bewildering the night extinguished in a flash—
曖昧な心が揺れて 声は響かず
an ambiguous heart wavers, and no voice echoes.
もっと触りたくて 夢をなぞる指先さえ
Wanting to touch more, even the fingertips tracing dreams
いつしか果てた形を忘れかけてた
had almost forgotten their form.
浮世の波に揺蕩ううたかたの夢は弾けていく
Ephemeral dreams swaying on the waves of this floating world burst apart.
宇陀の奥山に荒れる想い達は純情
Passions raging deep in the mountains of Uda are pure.
そうのらりくらり 心揺らめき歌うわ雪月花
Yes, wavering and wandering hearts sing of snow, moon, and flowers.
浅き夢見しと想い 踏み込むこの世界は
Stepping into this world, thinking it a fleeting dream—
誰も皆焦がれ出る 現世の理よ
all yearning is the principle of this mortal world.
色づく想いは切ない 百花繚乱 花吹雪
Colored thoughts are painful; a hundred flowers bloom in a storm of cherry blossoms.
一二三 数えて ここにさあおいで
Count one, two, three, and come right over here.
暁交わした約束は “本物”だってきっと信じてる
I surely believe the promise exchanged at dawn is "real."
色はにほへと の花に魅せられた少女たち
Maidens charmed by the fragrant, colorful blossoms—
ああ はらり はらり はらり 落ちる花と舞い踊れ
ah, flutter, flutter, falling petals, dance away!
惑わされずとも想い 言の葉に込めてみた
Though unstaggered, I put my feelings into words.
誰も皆焦がれ出る 現世の理よ
All yearning is the principle of this mortal world.
色づく想いは切ない 百花繚乱 花吹雪
Colored thoughts are painful; a hundred flowers bloom in a storm of cherry blossoms.
フッと引き消した 夜を戸惑う 月明かりに
In the moonlight bewildering the night extinguished in a flash—
曖昧な心が揺れて 声は響かず
an ambiguous heart wavers, and no voice echoes.
もっと触りたくて 夢をなぞる指先さえ
Wanting to touch more, even the fingertips tracing dreams—
いつしか果てた形を忘れかけてた 風に舞う乙女の純情 咲き誇れ
had almost forgotten their form. Maidens dancing in the wind, bloom proudly!
乙女の順序 咲き誇れ
Maidenly order, bloom proudly!
間違えた！
I messed up!
ちょっと間違えた！ちょっと間違えた！
I messed up a bit! I messed up!
でも可愛かったよね？
But it was cute, right?
でも楽しかった！
But it was fun!
みんな踊ってくれてありがとう！
Thank you everyone for dancing with us!
記念すべき日におめでとう！ありがとう！
Congratulations on this memorable day! Thank you!
じゃあ、ちょっと、今時間なんでね、おい！急いで
Well, we don't have much time, hey! Hurry up.
ステージ戻ります！
Returning to the stage!
がんばってね！バイバーイ！
Do your best! Bye-bye!
小さなキノコ見つける？
Find a tiny mushroom?
確かに。大きなキノコしか見つかってない
True. We only found big mushrooms.
もうちょっと1回さ、クレープ食べに行かないと意見分かれちゃった
We couldn't agree on whether to go eat crepes first.
休憩しよう！おいもも食べよう！
Let's take a break! Let's eat sweet potatoes too!
じゃあ、ちょっとクレープ食べてきまーす！
Well then, we're going to go eat crepes!
みんなお待たせしました！ ちょっと急いでね、あのアイドル一緒に着替えて戻ってきましたけれども
Sorry to keep you all waiting! We hurried up, changed with the idols, and came back, but...
えーここらへんでね、ちょっとちょっとお知らせをちょっとずつ挟んじゃおっかな、おっかなと
Um, around here, I wanted to slip in a little announcement bit by bit.
いうことでですね、何が来るかと言いますと
So, you might wonder what's coming next—
みんな行きますよ、重大発表ですよ！いいですか？ 心の準備はよろしいでしょうか？ ということで
everyone, here we go, a major announcement! Are you ready? Is your heart prepared?
百鬼あやめ 活動三周年記念グッズ発売します！やったー！
Nakiri Ayame's 3rd Anniversary Goods are now on sale! Yay!
ということで気になるね、活動三周年記念グッズのフルセットの内容はこちらです！どん！
So, here are the contents of the full set of 3rd anniversary goods you've been curious about! Ta-da!
抱き枕カバーとボイスのセットになっております！
It's a set including a dakimakura cover and voice packs!
あ、皆、ちょっと待って、
Ah, everyone, wait a second—
待ってないじゃないの？
you weren't actually waiting, were you?
ちょっとね、皆他のメンバーとかもね、出している中、あれ？
You know, while other members have been releasing theirs, like...
余さんの抱き枕カバーってまだないんですか？
"Wait, does Ayame-sama not have a body pillow cover yet?"
え？まだ出ないんですか？なんてね、
"Eh? It's still not coming out?"
え、お声も、まあ、あったりなかったりみたいな、あったんですけど！
Well, there were voices like that, or maybe not, but there were!
えーと、いうことで今回、街に待った抱き枕カバーを発売させていただきますよ！
So, with that said, we are finally releasing the long-awaited body pillow cover!
え、表面がですね、余のいつも着ている和服と裏面が夏仕様の水着となっております！
The front features Ayame's usual kimono, and the back features a summery swimsuit!
フルセットにはね、なんとなんと数量限定で直筆サイン入りのポストカードが付いていきます！
And the full set will come with a handwritten signed postcard in limited quantities!
よもね、がんばって一生懸命書きますよ！
Ayame will do her absolute best to write them!
でね、ちょっと数量に限りがあるので、えー数量を超えた場合は、えっと複写の金ピカのね余のサインがついてくることになります。
Since quantities are limited, if orders exceed the limit, it'll come with a printed gold-foil signature instead.
で、気になるシチュエーションボイスはですね、3周年記念「海デート」
And as for the much-anticipated situation voice, it's called "3rd Anniversary Ocean Date,"
ということボイスになっておりますので、是非皆さん、ちょっとね恥ずかしいですけど聞いてくれたら嬉しいなって思います。
so I hope you'll all listen to it—even though it's a bit embarrassing—and enjoy it!
で、これはね、描いてくださったのは母親のナカガラ、ナカガラ先生となっております！お母様ありがとうございます！
And this was drawn by Ayame's mother, Nakagara-sensei! Thank you so much, Mother!
で、ぜひぜひね、すいません、あの疲れちゃいましたね。
Sorry, I'm already getting kind of tired.
え、ぜひぜひ皆さんお買い求めくださいませ！
Everyone, please be sure to check it out and buy it!
ということで、もう、あの、お城すもしたことですし、もう、あの、3周年の配信も、もう、ここらへんでもまあ、いっかなー。
So, since we've made the announcement, I guess we can pretty much wrap up this 3rd-anniversary stream right here—
なんてことないですよ！
No way, of course not!
皆さん、あと一つお知らせがありますからね！
Everyone, I have one more announcement for you!
なんと、皆さんこれこそ街に待ったんじゃないかという
I'm sure this is something you've all truly been waiting for!
ことがありますね！ありますね？
Am I right? Is there something?
そうです！余がまだ出していないものがまだ一つありますね！そう！
That's right! There's still one thing Ayame hasn't released yet! That's right!
余のオリジナルソングをここで発表したいと思います！やったー！
I'd like to announce my original song right here! Yay!
ということで、え、皆さまをお待たせした余の1曲目のね記念すべきオリジナルソングが
And so, the long-awaited first original song commemorating Ayame's anniversary
ちょっとここで、お披露目されますので、みんなね、ちょっと愛の手とかも覚えていってくれたら嬉しいななんて思います。
will be unveiled right here, so I hope you'll all learn the call-and-response and enjoy it!
もう余ね、表した曲なんで是非聞いていってください！
It's a song that really expresses Ayame, so please listen to it!
じゃ、いきますよ！よ、オリジナルソングで「宵の余、良い？」
Now, here we go! Ayame's original song, "Yoi no Yo, Ii?"
宵の余、良い？
Is Ayame's evening alright?
夜毎 夜毎 今夜は眠れない
Night after night, I can't sleep tonight
連日 連夜 遊び尽くそう なんちゃって！
Day and night, let's play to our heart's content! Just kidding!
天真爛漫 溢れてくる フルフル 好奇心
Innocent and brimming with overflowing curiosity
融通不聞 これで決めよう じゃんけんぽいよと合図でしょ
Let's decide this with a game of janken, right on cue!
パッとパッと開いた 花火を打ち上げよう
Let's launch fireworks blooming brightly in the sky!
歌え 踊れ 右に倣え よーよーピカピカの宴
Sing, dance, follow the lead, a shiny, sparkling feast!
さあ 騒げ 夜が明くまで 華やかなお庭番
Come on, make noise until dawn, glamorous Niwaban!
歌え 踊れ 万に習え ポンコツ それすらも愛嬌
Sing, dance, follow all rules, even being a blunderer is charming
さあ 騒げ 赤きまで 華やかなお庭番
Come on, make noise until it's red, glamorous Niwaban!
あー 手加減ない 踊り明かそう 斎場 踊る 踊り納め
Ah, no holding back, let's dance the night away at the final dance
音にのせられて 縦に横に世代を超えて 全身で まー、よーいよーいよーい！
Carried by the sound, vertically and horizontally across generations, with all my heart—yoi, yoi, yoi!
目を閉じ 深呼吸 一息入れてじゃあね
Close your eyes, take a deep breath, catch your breath and bye-bye
耳噛み 味わえ 働け 必死だった
Nibble ears, savor it, work hard, we were desperate
えいえいむ - もう終わりたくない
Ei-ei-mu—I don't want it to end yet
何をして遊ぼうか
What should we play next?
アンチュモサク これで決めよう じゃんけんぽいよと合図でしょ
Let's decide this through trial and error, with a game of janken!
グッとぐっと応えて
Respond with all your might
よーよー よーよー
Yoyo, yoyo
パットパット まくほど 太鼓 打ち鳴らせ
Beat the drums as much as you can scatter
泣いて 笑え よに続け キラキラの ピピカ かかげ
Cry, laugh, continue onward, raise that sparkling pipika!
さあ おいでおてんば よせてまくれんな お庭番
Come here, tomboy, gather and roll up, Niwaban!
ちゃんちゃらおかしな出で立ちで
Dressed in a ridiculously absurd outfit,
立って 笑え 前に進め
stand up, laugh, and move forward!
狐につままれても良いぞさあおいで
Even if you're bewitched by a fox, it's fine. Come on over,
遠慮も無用
no need to hold back,
華麗な庭うち ああ 報告せとそう
in this gorgeous garden! Ah, reporting in,
夜をかざるまぶしい声に釣られて
drawn in by the dazzling voice lighting up the night,
なんだか最高
somehow it's the absolute best,
跳ねにまた天心だ もいよいいよよい
bounding up once again to the feast, yoi-yoi-yoi!
夜だぞ 心をもっともっと盛り上げるために みんなねあいの手をおろそうともよ
It's night! To get everyone's spirits even higher, let's all clap along,
読み続けてちゃんと続いてきてね 行くよせーの
keep reading and follow right along! Here we go, ready, set—
よいよいよいのよいのよいのよい
Yoi-yoi-yoi-yoi-yoi-yoi-yoi!
ほうあんあん ぱっぱらぱの行進やってやる
Hou-an-an, let's do the pappara-pa march!
ほらバケツ叩いては声上げろや
Hey, beat the buckets and raise your voices!
ほう明るい夜の到着だ
Hou, the arrival of the bright night!
歌え踊れ 右に回れ 息を呼べ ピカいちの歌い手
Sing, dance, spin to the right, catch your breath, you top-notch singer!
さあ騒げ 夜の奴隷 華麗なお庭うち
Now make some noise, slaves of the night, in this gorgeous garden!
歌え踊れ 前に習え ボンコツ それすらも愛嬌
Sing, dance, follow in line, even being a clumsy clunker has its charm!
さあ騒げ 赤月まで 華麗なお庭うち
Now make some noise until the red moon rises, in this gorgeous garden!
正客万来 ご招待 からさいをさらを 音に乗せられて なんてなんて世代
A full house of guests, you're invited, swept away by the rhythm—what an era!
華麗に参上 天下の舞 良いのよいのよい
Making a grand appearance, the dance of the realm, yoi-yoi-yoi!
ポンポンポンポン
Pom-pom-pom-pom!